A Guide to the Black, Kent, and Apperson, Families, Papers, 1779-1984
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
- Black Family Business Records, 1832-1924
  - Account Books, 1832-1908, 5 ledgers
    - Black family (?), 1898-1901 (Box 7)
    - A.W. Luster, 1854-1886 (Box 8)
      This ledger includes an inventory, July 1908, for W. Stone & Son.
  - Receipts, 1853-1906 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Investments, 1889-1924 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    This subseries is comprised of documents pertaining to investments in the Radford Land Improvement Company, 1889; the Radford West End Land Company, 1909; and oil drilling operations in Texas, 1912-1924.
  - Ephemera, 1928, n.d., 2 items (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Copy of a newspaper advertisement for A. Black, Inc., n.d.
    - Luster and Black letterhead, 1928
  - Political Ephemera, 1882-1896, two items (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Address of the Readjuster Members of the Legislature to the People", 1882
    - Sample ballot, Peter J. Otey for Congress, Sixth District, 1896
- John S. Apperson Papers, 1858-1915
  - Biographical Information, 1898, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs, c.1893-1895 (Box 9, Folder 3-7)
    - John S. Apperson at the Colombian Exposition, 1893
    - John S. Apperson, c.1893
    - John S. Apperson, Elizabeth B. Apperson, and their children, c.1895
  - Account books, 1858-1859 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Civil War Diaries, 1859-1865 (Box 10)
    - Transcript of Apperson diaries, c.1990 (Box 9, Folder 9-23)
  - Business Records, 1862-1915 (Box 9, Folder 24-27)
    This subseries is comprised of miscellaneous receipts, 1862; Business Correspondence, 1900-1910; and a catalog for the Marion Foundry and Machine Works, 1915.
  - Colombian Exposition, Medal and Commission, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 28, Box 10)
  - Literary Treatise, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Last Will and Testament, 1908 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Mary Apperson Papers, 1889-1977
  - Correspondence, 1889-1977 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - William H. Palmer to Elizabeth Black Apperson, 1889
    - Elizabeth B. Apperson letters regarding the illness of the daughter of Mrs. Cyprus McCormick and John S. Apperson (copies), n.d.
    - Regarding Germanicus Kent and Rockford, Illinois, 1966, 1977
    - Regarding Harvey Black Memorial Plaque at Virginia Tech, 1938-1939
      - Elizabeth B. Apperson
      - Mary Apperson
  - Speeches and Writings, 1936-1974 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
    - "History of Blacksburg, Virginia," as told to Mary Apperson by her mother, Elizabeth Black Apperson, 1936
    - "History of Blacksburg," notes and remarks by Mary Apperson, 1944
    - Notes on Blacksburg history, 1974
    - Notebook with notes on Blacksburg history and buildings, 1936
  - Clippings, 1884-1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    This file contains newspaper clippings on Blacksburg history and members of the Black, Kent, and Apperson families.
  - Publications, 1947-1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Rockford College Centennial Calendar", 1947
    - "A History of the Blacksburg Presbyterian Church", 1953
    - "Bulletin of the Rockford Historical Society, Rockford, Illinois", 1965-1967
    - "Directory of Service Clubs of Winnebago County, Illinois", 1977
      The Directory's cover illustration is a photograph of a sculpture commemorating the role played by Germanicus Kent and Lewis Lemon, Kent's former slave, in the founding of Rockford, Illinois.
    - "A Guide to Memorial Hall, Rockford, Illinois", 1977
    - Booklet, "Germanicus A. Kent, Founder of Rockford, Illinois", c.1977
    - "History of the Kent Memorial Library, Suffield, Connecticut", n.d.
  - Photograph of Lewis A. Kent, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Family Artifacts, 1885-1949 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - List of relics from the family of Germanicus Kent used in the Germanicus Kent Exhibition in Rockford, Illinois, 1949
    - Gloves, handkerchief used by Mary Lou Black, 1885 (Box 18)
    - Poem about Mountain Lake by Caroline Otey Pleasants, 1893 (Box 18)
- Alexander Apperson Papers, 1827-1984
  This series is comprised primarily of research files on the genealogy of the Black, Kent, Apperson and related families. It also contains family photographs, including a picture of the Alexander Black House, later burned, ca. 1900; a folder of correspondence pertaining to Alexander Black's service on the vestry of Mountainbrook Methodist Church in Birmingham, Alabama, 1944-1954; a 1914 edition of "The X-Ray," the yearbook of Marion High School; and a program from the 1962 annual convention of the Virginia Division of the United Daughters of the Confederacy.
  - Family Photographs, c.1900-1970 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1953 (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
    This subseries is comprised of one folder of correspondence pertaining to a proposed memorial to Harvey Black at Virginia Tech from 1953; one folder of correspondence pertaining to Mountainbrook Methodist Church in Birmingham, Alabama, 1944-1954, and one letter, 1934, from A.J. Oliver to Harvey Black Apperson, discussing Oliver's father, who worked for Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College in the 1870s and helped plant the first trees on the campus.
  - Conventions and Personal Memorabilia, 1914, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    This subseries is comprised of the Marion High School yearbook, 1914; and a program from the Sixty-seventh Annual Convention of the Virginia Division of the United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1962.
  - Genealogy Research, 1827-1984
    This subseries is comprised of correspondence, applications to family heritage organizations, and copies of documents pertaining to genealogy research on the Black, Kent, Apperson, and related families.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of family being researched.
    - Apperson Family, 1902-1979 (Box 11, Folder 17-27)
      - Letter, Edgar Apperson to Hull Apperson, 1920
      - "Apperson Family History," by John A. Apperson, 1902
      - Mrs. John S. (Elizabeth Black) Apperson membership certificate, United Daughters of the Confederacy Building Association, Virginia Division, 1907
      - Research notes on John Apperson and his family, c.1975
      - Research on Apperson Family Genealogy and letter from Mrs. John Ross Apperson, 1966
      - Apperson Family Genealogy, c.1975
      - Correspondence regarding genealogy research, 1958-1979, two folders
      - Birth and death records copied from Apperson family Bible, Emory and Henry College
    - Amiss family, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Black family, 1872-1894 (Box 12, Folder 3-11)
      - Copy of the 1789 Last Will and Testament of Samuel Black, 1872
      - Copy of the 1900 Last Will and Testament of Cecilia White, n.d.
      - "Sketches of the History of the Black Family from England to the United States," by Florence Black Weiland and Ellen Tyler McDonald, c.1936
      - Genealogy and Historical Sketches of the Black Family, 1954, 1972
      - Black Family, 1979-1984, two folders
      - Black and Mastin families
      - Black family in Wisconsin, 1979
      - "Virginia Military Hospitals," by Henrietta Runyon Winfrey, c.1953
    - Crockett family, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dudley family, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - Epperson family, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Copy of "Old Record of the Captivity of Margaret Erskine, 1779", n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Kent family, 1827-1979 (Box 13, Folder 3-8)
      - Kent Family, c.1970, two folders
      - "A Brief Account of the Kents of Wytheville and the County and Houses they Built and Lived In," by Joseph Gordon Kent and Mary C. Withers, 1927, 1939
      - E. Lacontine Wytheville Correspondence, 1827-1857, three items; in French
      - Germanicus Kent, 1975-1979
      - William Leete
    - Mastin family, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Porter family, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Benjamin Ruggles, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Tynes family, c.1968, 2 items (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Woodbridge family, c.1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Applications for membership in genealogy societies, 1920-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14-17)
      This subseries is comprised of documents pertaining to applications, by members of the Black family, for membership in the Daughters of the American Revolution, Huguenot Society, Magna Carta Barons, National Society of Colonial Wars, and the Society of Colonial Dames.
    - Miscellaneous research, 1834-1967 (Box 13, Folder 18-22)
      - Copies of 1796 land purchase records, Smyth County, Virginia, 1834, 1839
      - Research and biographical sketch of Judge Andrew S. Alexander
      - Annotated copy of "Notes on Draper's Meadows and Blacksburg and Vicinity"
      - Annotated folders that previously housed the genealogy research files donated by Alexander Apperson
- Harvey B. Apperson Political Scrapbooks, 1933-1950, Five scrapbooks and one box of items removed from the scrapbooks and copied for preservation. Photographs and ephemera removed from the scrapbooks are stored in Box 15. (Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Folder 1-10)
  This series is comprised of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings, incoming correspondence and telegrams, photographs, and ephemera documenting Harvey Apperson's political career from 1933, when he ran for the State Senate, to his death in 1948, four months after Governor William Tuck appointed him Attorney General.
- Blacksburg Manufacturing and Mining Company, 1953-1965 (Box 17, Folder 1-6, Folder 1)
  This series is comprised of deeds, reports, correspondence, lease agreements, and receipts pertaining to Apperson family investments in mining operations at Poverty Hollow, Tom's Creek Road, the Blacksburg Manufacturing and Mining Company, and M.C. Slusser and Company. It also contains maps of Blacksburg Manufacturing and Mining Company coal land sold to the Hoge heirs in 1928 and maps showing property owned by the Alexander and Lizzie O. Black estate and Apperson Properties in 1937 and 1948.
- Louise Caton Travel Diary, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  The diary is an account of Louise Caton's voyage from New York to Genoa, Italy, her travels through Italy, Switzerland, Germany, Holland, France, and England, and her return from Liverpool to New York in the summer of 1912.
- The Christian Union, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 8)